Guide to the James Olinkiewicz Collection of Brooklyn Daily Eagle Postcards 1905-1907 PR 355
New-York Historical Society
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 48, 1906 October 8-13 (Box 1 of 1)
  288 | St. James Pro Cathedral, Jay and Chapel Streets.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 49, 1906 October 15-20 (Box 1 of 1)
  289 | Battleship "Colorado" in Dry Dock at Navy Yard.
  290 | Montague Street Hill in 1850.
  291 | Miss Annie Russell, who will appear at the New Montauk Theatre in "A Midsummer Night's Dream," Week of October 22d.
  292 | First Presbyterian Church, Henry St., near Clark.
  293 | Public School No. 32, Hoyt St., cor. President St.
  294 | Water Front at 65th Street.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 50, 1906 October 22-27 (Box 1 of 1)
  295 | Congregation Beth Israel, Tompkins Place and Harrison Street.
  296 | Nassau Trust Co. Bldg., 136 Broadway.
  297 | Public School No. 9, Vanderbilt Avenue and Sterling Place.
  298 | Fort Lafayette, at Entrance to Narrows.
  299 | Fire Department Building on Jay Street.
  300 | Scene from "The Tourists," the Attraction at the Shubert Theatre, Week of Nov. 5th.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 51, 1906 October 29-November 3 (Box 1 of 1)
  301 | Kings County Jail, Raymond Street.
  302 | Sands Street Memorial M.E. Church, Henry Street, cor. Clark.
  303 | Public School 79, Kosciusko St., near Throop Ave.
  304 | St. Malachy's Home, Rockaway Park.
  305 | Shubert Theatre, Fulton Street, Opposite City Hall.
  306 | Miss Ethel Barrymore, who will appear in "Alice-sit-by-the-Fire" at the New Montauk, Week of November 5th [1906].
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 52, 1906 November 5-10 (Box 1 of 1)
  307 | The Old Erasmus Hall and Dr. Walter B. Gunnison, Principal.
  308 | St. Paul's Episcopal Church, Clinton and Carroll Streets and Rev. Werner E.L. Ward, Rector.
  309 | St. Joseph's Holy Name Society Marching up Eastern Parkway.
  310 | Hyde and Behman's Theater on Admas Street.
  311 | Far Rockaway Public Library.
  312 | Jamaica Plank Road, 1867. Returning from Snedeker's.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 53, 1906 November 12-17 (Box 1 of 1)
  313 | Ansonia Clock Company, 7th and 8th Aves. And 12th and 13th Sts. Largest Clock Factory in the World.
  314 | St. John's Evan. Lutheran Church, Maujer St.
  315 | Public School No. 108, Arlington Ave. and Linwood St.
  316 | Methodist Home, Park Place.
  317 | Grand Opera House, Elm Pl. near Fulton St.
  318 | Summer Residence of the Boys of St. Philip's Home at Bath Beach.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 54, 1906 November 19-24 (Box 1 of 1)
  319 | The Baptist Home, Greene Ave. cor. Throop.
  320 | Public School No. 134, 18th Ave. and Ocean Parkway.
  321 | Ferry House, foot of Atlantic Avenue, Brooklyn, in 1850.
  322 | Arlington Avenue Presbyterian Church.
  323 | The Morgue.
  324 | Miss Elsie Janis, Star of "The Vanderbilt Cup," at the Montauk Theater [sic] Week of November 26th [1906].
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 55, 1906 November 26-December 1 (Box 1 of 1)
  325 | Miss Lena Ashwell, the Distinguished English Actress, now Appearing in "The Shulamite."
  326 | Lafayette Avenue Presbyterian Church.
  327 | Public School No. 128, 21st Avenue and 83d Street.
  328 | Naval Prison, Brooklyn Navy Yard.
  329 | Home for Aged Men and Couples, Classon Avenue.
  330 | Brooklyn Terminal of 39th Street Ferry.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 56, 1906 December 3-8 (Box 1 of 1)
  331 | Miss Hattie Williams, now Starring in "The Little Cherub," Booked for the Montauk, Dec. 10th.
  332 | Public School No. 83, Bergen Street and Schenectady Avenue.
  333 | 14th Regiment Armory, 8th Avenue and 14th Street.
  334 | United States Battleship Kearsarge.
  335 | Flatbush Avenue. Melrose Park on Right.
  336 | German Reformed Church, Herkimer Street near Ralph Avenue.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 57, 1906 December 10-15 (Box 1 of 1)
  337 | St. Peter's Church, Hicks and Warren Streets.
  338 | Public School No. 10, Seventh Avenue, corner 17th Street.
  339 | Elks' Club House on Schermerhorn Street.
  340 | 71st Precinct Police Station on 86th Street.
  341 | Junction of Flatbush Avenue and Fulton Street.
  342 | Scene from "The Love Route," Christmas Week Attraction at the Shubert Theatre.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 58, 1906 December 17-22 (Box 1 of 1)
  343 | Thomas Jefferson Building, Court Square, near Fulton Street.
  344 | Telephone Building, Willoughby and Lawrence Streets.
  345 | John Drew, who is Starring in "His House in Order." The Xmas week attraction at the Montauk Theatre.
  346 | St. Benedict's Parochial School, Herkimer Street, near Ralph Avenue.
  347 | Public School No. 46, Union Street, near Henry.
  348 | Williamsburg Bridge Plaza.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 59, 1906 December 24-29 (Box 1 of 1)
  349 | American Sugar Refining Company, East River, Ket Avenue, between South First and South Second Streets. The Largest in the World.
  350 | Brooklyn Real Estate Exchange, Montague Street.
  351 | The "Old Jersey" Prison Ship, 1776.
  352 | Ross Street Presbyterian Church, Ross Street, near Lee Avenue.
  353 | Joseph Cawthorne in "The Free Lance" at the Montauk Theatre New Year's Week.
  354 | Clermont Roller Rink.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 60, 1906 December 31-1907 January 5 (Box 1 of 1)
  355 | Lawyers' Title Insurance Company, Montague Street.
  356 | Miss May Irwin, now Starring in "Mrs. Wilson Andrews," the Montauk Theatre Attraction, Week January 7th, 1907.
  357 | Ferry House Foot of Fulton Street, Brooklyn, in 1850.
  358 | 23d Regiment Armory, Bedford Avenue and Pacific Street.
  359 | Church of St. Charles Barromeo [sic], Sydney Place and Livingston Street.
  360 | Public School No. 124 Fourth Avenue and Fourteenth Street.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 61, 1907 January 7-12 (Box 1 of 1)
  361 | Miss Mabel McKinley, to Appear at Hyde & Behman's Theatre Week of January 14, 1907.
  362 | First Reformed Church of Brooklyn on Livingston Street in 1835.
  363 | Public School No. 36, Stagg Street, near Bushwick Avenue.
  364 | Lee Avenue Congregational Church, Lee Avenue, cor. Hooper Street.
  365 | St. Vincent's New Home for Boys.
  366 | Beautiful Residential Section of Flatbush — Avenue G, East of Ocean Avenue.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 62, 1907 January 14-19 (Box 1 of 1)
  367 | Beautiful Albemarle Road, Prospect Park South.
  368 | Hospital of the Old People's Home on Chauncey Street.
  369 | David Warfield in a Scene From "The Music Master," Booked for the Shubert, Week of January 21, 1907.
  370 | Classon Avenue Presbyterian Church, Classon Avenue and Monroe Street.
  371 | Crescent Club's New Home, Clinton and Pierrepont Street.
  372 | St. Francis College, Baltic Street near Court.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 63, 1907 January 21-26 (Box 1 of 1)
  373 | St. John's Parochial School, Lewis and Willoughby Avenues.
  374 | Grace Methodist Episcopal Church, Seventh Avenue, Corner St. John's Place.
  375 | Two Old Mansions, Southwest Corner Stuyvesant Avenue and Bainbridge Street. Erected Over Fifty Years Ago.
  376 | Kings County Trust Co. Building on Fulton St.
  377 | Miss Fay Templeton in "Forty-Five Minutes from Broadway," at the Montauk, Week of January 21, 1907.
  378 | A Winter Scene in Prospect Park.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 64, 1907 January 28-February 2 (Box 1 of 1)
  379 | Franklin Avenue Presbyterian Church, Franklin Avenue, Near Myrtle.
  380 | The Vechte-Cortelyou House at Gowanus in 1699.
  381 | Public School 13, Degraw Street, Near Hicks.
  382 | Williamsburg Trust Company Building, Fulton Street, Opposite Borough Hall.
  383 | View of Willoughby Street, off. Fulton
  384 | Miss Maud Adams as "Peter Pan," the Montauk Theatre Attraction, Week of January 28, 1907.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 65, 1907 February 4-9 (Box 1 of 1)
  385 | Telephone Building, Willoughby and Lawrence Streets.
  386 | Fountain in the Old City Hall Park.
  387 | Type of Very Old Houses on Baltic Street, near Smith.
  388 | South Second Street M.E. Church.
  389 | Hotel St. George, Clark and Hicks Streets.
  390 | Scene from "The New York Idea," to be Produced at the Shubert Theatre February 11, 1907. Mrs. Fiske, the Star.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 66, 1907 February 11-16 (Box 1 of 1)
  391 | Hecla Iron Works, North Eleventh and Berry Streets.
  392 | Commercial High School, Albany Avenue, between Dean and Bergen Streets.
  393 | Abraham Lincoln, by H. Stanley Todd. Photo copyright by Stark Co., N.Y.
  394 | Dorothy Donnelly, Starring in "The Daughters of Men," Appearing at the Montauk February 11, 1907.
  395 | Second United Presbyterian Church, Atlantic Ave. and Bond St.
  396 | Gardener's Lodge (Battle Hill), Greenwood Cemetery, in 1840.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 67, 1907 February 18-23 (Box 1 of 1)
  397 | Public School No. 25, Lafayette Avenue, near Throop.
  398 | Church of Our Lady of Mercy, Debevoise Place, near DeKalb Avenue.
  399 | Jessie Millward in the "Hypocrites" at the Montauk, Week February 18th [1907].
  400 | Knox Hat Factory, St. Marks and Grand Avenues.
  401 | George Washington.
  402 | The Mohawk Apartments, Washington Avenue, near Greene.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 68, 1907 February 25-March 2 (Box 1 of 1)
  403 | Squadron C Armory, Bedford Avenue and Eastern Parkway.
  404 | Skating on Prospect Park Lake.
  405 | Greene Avenue Presbyterian Church, Greene Avenue, near Patchen.
  406 | Brooklyn, as Seen from Trinity Church, New York, in 1853.
  407 | Public School 57, Reid Ave., cor. Van Buren St.
  408 | Mr. William Gillette.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 69, 1907 March 4-9 (Box 1 of 1)
  409 | U.S. Cruiser "Minneapolis."
  410 | Prosenium Arch of the Beautiful Shubert Theatre.
  411 | P.S. No. 78, Pacific St., near Court.
  412 | Kings Co. Savings Inst., B'way and Bedford Ave.
  413 | Frederick Loeser & Co. Department Store, Fulton Street.
  414 | Irving Square Presbyterian Church, Hamburg Ave. and Weirfield St.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 70, 1907 March 11-16 (Box 1 of 1)
  415 | Washington Ave. Baptist Church, Washington Ave. Cor. Gates.
  416 | P.S. No. 21, McKibbin St., near Manhattan Ave.
  417 | Scene from Act I of "The Light Eternal," the Shubert Theatre Attraction, Week of March 25th [1907].
  418 | Brooklyn Bridge.
  419 | "Tunisian," of the Allan State Line.
  420 | The Elks in Prospect Park.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 71, 1907 March 18-23 (Box 1 of 1)
  421 | Jessie Busley in "The Bishop's Carriage," at the Montauk Theatre, March 25th [1907].
  422 | Labon's Inn, 1853. Present Site of Journeay & Burnham on Flatbush Avenue.
  423 | Public School No. 70, Patchen Avenue, Corner Macon Street.
  424 | Temple Beth-Elohim, Keap St., near Division Ave.
  425 | Convent of Mercy, 12th Avenue and 64th Street.
  426 | A Bit of Woodland in Prospect Park.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 72, 1907 March 25-30 (Box 1 of 1)
  427 | Scene from "The Road to Yesterday," the Shubert Theatre, Attraction Week of April 8th [1907].
  428 | Erie Basin and Gowanus Canal.
  429 | Ferry House Foot of Montague Street, 1850.
  430 | Baptist Temple, Schermerhorn St. and Third Ave.
  431 | Old Vanderveer Mill, Canarsie, Over 200 Years Old.
  432 | Public School No. 18, Maujer St., near Ewen St.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 73, 1907 April 1-6 (Box 1 of 1)
  433 | Abraham & Straus' Department Store on Fulton Street.
  434 | Charlotte Walker and Vincent Serrano in "On Parole," the Shubert Theatre Attraction, Week of April 1st [1907].
  435 | Public School No. 40, Fifteenth Street, near Fourth Avenue.
  436 | Warren St. M.E. Church and Parsonage, Warren St., near Smith.
  437 | Frozen Lake in the Vale of Cashmere, Prospect Park.
  438 | Handsome Residences on Albemarle Road, Flatbush.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 74, 1907 April 8-13 (Box 1 of 1)
  439 | Mr. Richard Mansfield, Booked for the Montauk Theatre, Week of April 8th [1907].
  440 | A.D. Matthews' Sons' Department Store, Fulton Street.
  441 | Public School No. 44, Throop and Putnam Avenues.
  442 | St. Peter's Lutheran Church, Bedford Ave.
  443 | Edgett's Restaurant, Fulton St. and Flatbush Ave.
  444 | Old Homestead at Vanderveer Farm, Canarsie, Over 200 Years Old.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 75, 1907 April 15-20 (Box 1 of 1)
  445 | Scene from First Act of "Mme. Butterfly," the Japanese Grand Opera, to be Presented at the Montauk Theatre, Week of April 22nd [1907].
  446 | The Montague Apartment Hotel, Montague St.
  447 | Public School No. 56, Bushwick Avenue, cor. Madison Street.
  448 | Second United Presbyterian Church, Bond St., cor. Atlantic Ave.
  449 | Brooklyn Hebrew Orphan Asylum.
  450 | Statue of "Lion and Cubs" in Prospect Park.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 76, 1907 April 22-27 (Box 1 of 1)
  451 | Lillian Blauvelt and Maurice Farkoa in "The Magic Knight," in Joe Weber's Production at the Shubert, Week of April 22nd [1907].
  452 | Wide Stretch of Ocean Avenue.
  453 | Memorial Church, Seventh Avenue and St. John's Place.
  454 | Concourse Park, Coney Island.
  455 | Public School No. 7, York, near Bridge Street.
  456 | Farm House, Prospect Park.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 77, 1907 April 29-May 4 (Box 1 of 1)
  457 | Avenue G, Looking East from Coney Island Avenue.
  458 | Steamship "Hamburg," Hamburg-American Line.
  459 | Three-Arch Bridge in Prospect Park.
  460 | Scene from "The Three of Us," the Shubert Theatre Attraction, Week of May 6th [1907].
  461 | Protestant Episcopal Church of the Messiah, Greene Avenue cor. Clermont Avenue.
  462 | Public School No. 75, Evergreen Ave., cor. Ralph.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 78, 1907 May 6-11 (Box 1 of 1)
  463 | Emanuel Baptist Church, Lafayette Ave. and St. James Place.
  464 | Public School No. 16, Wilson Street, near Bedford Avenue.
  465 | Thomas W. Ross, now Starring in "The Other Girl," the Shubert Theatre Attraction, Week of May 13th [1907].
  466 | Mt. Prospect Pumping Station.
  467 | Imperial Apartment House, Bedford Avenue and Dean Street.
  468 | Lotus Basin, Prospect Park.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 79, 1907 May 13-18 (Box 1 of 1)
  469 | Public School No. 44, Throop Avenue, corner Putnam.
  470 | St. Peter's P.E. Church, State Street near Bond. Rev. Lindsay Parker, Pastor.
  471 | H. Batterman's Department Store, Broadway, Graham and Flushing Aves.
  472 | Path Leading to the Flower Garden, Prospect Park.
  473 | The Orpheum Theatre, Fulton Street and Rockwell Place.
  474 | Shore Drive Looking North from Ninety-Second Street.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 80, 1907 May 20-25 (Box 1 of 1)
  475 | United States Navy Yard, Looking North to the East River.
  476 | The Swans on Prospect Park Lake.
  477 | Folly Theatre.
  478 | Public School No. 18, Maujer Street, near Leonard.
  479 | Central Congregational Church, Hancock St. near Bedford Ave., Rev. S. Parkes Cadman, Pastor.
  480 | Thirteenth Regiment Armory on Sumner, Jefferson and Putnam Avs [sic].
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 81, 1907 May 27-June 1 (Box 1 of 1)
  481 | Miss Blance [Blanche?] Bates and Mr. Frank Keenan in a Scene from "The Girl of the Golden West," the Shubert Theatre Attraction Week of May 27th [1907].
  482 | Eagle Warehouse and Storage Co., of Brooklyn, 28 to 44 Fulton Street.
  483 | Public School 119, East Thirty-ninth Street and Avenue K.
  484 | Second Presbyterian Church, Clinton Street, cor. Remsen.
  485 | Crowd on the Coney Island Bowery.
  486 | A Nook in Prospect Park.